[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
so this is our lesson four
where I'm gonna teach you
how to install test automation extension
in your browsers
and also I'm gonna introduce you to the
system under test that we are gonna use
while automating our test cases by using
Tasker in the upcoming lessons
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so our first agenda is Introduction
to System under test so what is system
under test
it's an application
that you would like to automate or test
by using Tasker that is called a system
under test okay so in our lessons when
we are automating the test cases we are
going to use a demo
webshop.trycentish.com that is a website
that is being built by trisantis people
and this is
open to the public
so you can register to this website and
start automating your test cases for
training purpose okay so this is what we
are going to refer in our upcoming
sessions while automating our test cases
okay I'm gonna just give you a
walkthrough of this entire system under
test I'm gonna show you what are all the
different functionalities that are
available and what kind of test cases
that we are going to automate in the
upcoming lessons okay
stay tuned so what is our second agenda
item our second agenda item is
installing Tasker automation extension
in your browsers
okay so why do you we need
task automation extension
because so when you are actually
automating any application by using task
on we will be using a task scan
okay so when you are actually scanning
your page by using task scan
creates X browser modules to test your
web application
okay so to work with these created X
browser modules
X browser engine has been built by
sentence Tasker
so to work with this x browser engine
you need to install Tasker automation
extension for your browsers okay so for
Chrome you have an extension for Mozilla
Firefox you have an extension for Edge
you have an extension okay so to install
the extension follow the link that I
have pasted in the description okay you
can see on the screen also that is the
link that I'm gonna use to install the
Costco automation extension in different
browsers okay now let's jump out of the
system and let me show you
what is our system under test web
application
and let me walk you through the entire
application and also let me show you how
can we install test automation extension
okay so let's jump on to the system and
see
so demo webshop is our system under test
so what is system under test as I
explained to you
the application that you would like to
test by using Tasker is called system
under test okay so this is demo webshop
it's almost like
um
e-commerce site that is being built by
trisentis and this is
available for the public okay anyone can
register and use this website okay so
this has login so once you click on
login you need to provide your
email
and then password okay so this this web
you need to understand this website very
well because we are going to start
working on this website to automate all
our test cases okay this is our system
under test for
our upcoming automation sessions okay so
you can select any item from the menu so
let's say I want to buy a present shoes
select and then I want to add a blue
jeans to the cart add to the cut
as soon as you add blue jeans to the
cart it's going to show product has been
added to your shopping cart so then go
to shopping cart
and here
either you can provide your discount
codes coupons and apply the coupon or
you can provide your gift card code and
add gift card so that you will get some
discount right and you need to agree
before you check out the item so agree
and then check out the item so while
checking out the item you need to
provide your billing address okay either
you can provide new billing address or
you can use an existing billing address
and click on continue
and then what is your shipping address
so I want to select my shipping address
as same as billing address or you can
select in-store pickup right and click
on continue and then shipping methods
you have several shipping methods that
you can verify so you have different
functionality right you can verify so if
you want to automate by using ground if
you want to automate by using next day
second day here so the price will differ
okay so if you see 10 price 40 20 or
something like that okay and then click
on continue and then you have different
methods of payments you can test you can
automate cash and delivery payment you
can automate check Money credit card
purchase I want to select cash on
delivery for now click on continue
and then you can again you will pay by
Cod and then click on continue
and then here you need to verify your
entire billing address shipping address
payment method shipping method and
what's the price quantity correct what
is the tax
and then additional fee
and what is your total amount right once
you verify this you can click confirm
that means your order will be placed
successfully and order number will be
generated
okay so this way you can shop anything
books computers Electronics all the all
of the all the things okay log out if
you want to register to this website you
can click on register
provide your gender first name last name
email address password and confirm
password that's it very simple Okay so
yourself just get registered to this
website so that you will be ready for
our next automation sessions okay
so then what is our next agenda next
agenda is
how can we install
task automation extension in browsers
okay let's say I want to install
automation extension
task automation extension in Chrome
how to do that okay so this is the link
I provided I'm gonna paste the same Link
in the description also so this is the
link so you follow the same link here
and go down and then click on let's say
I want to Chrome Google Chrome right I'm
going to open this link
I want a extension for the Chrome
and then here if you come down there is
a link directly
our version is Tasker 16 that's why I
would like to use tricentice task 13.2
and upwards click on this
so this will take you to the Chrome web
store okay or you can directly go to
your Chrome Web Store and search for the
task automation extension so because I
already added let me remove from chrome
so that I can show you okay so once you
land onto this page you will have add to
Chrome button click on add to Chrome
and then click on ADD extension as soon
as you add the extension will be added
here if you see here the extension I'm
showing it's showing on Chrome
as an extension
done so let's say if you want to add
extension in the edge open your edge
browser
go to your Edge add-ons
and then search for
task automation extension
as soon as you search you will get a
search result here task automation
extension for Microsoft Edge
click on get
click on ADD extension immediately the
extension will be added see I can see
now extension for my Edge okay so this
is how you can add
automation extension for Edge and chrome
so why do we need this we need task
automation
Chrome browser sorry extension
for automating your system under test by
using browsers because when you are
actually
automating your system under test by
using task we are going to use xcan so
that you can create X browser modules
what do you mean by Xbox browser modules
for now you can think it has object
repository okay in the object repository
all the element locators will be added
in the form of X browser modules X
browser modules okay so to have this
browser modules or to access your X
browser engine of your Tasker this task
automation extension is necessary okay
so hope you all understand
our system under test
and how can you install Tasker
automation extension in the browser so
if you have any queries please provide
your queries in the comment box I will
try to respond to your queries thank you
hope you all understand the concepts of
system under test web application
and how can we install Tasker automation
extension in different browsers
so if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll respond
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]